(719) 359-3188

dave.z.harris@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/davezharris

#### HIGHLIGHTS OF PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Retired Army signal captain with 14 years' operational and team leadership experience, project and program management experience, Lean Six Sigma training, and MBA education. Seeking employment with a company in the area of operations or management.

## **KEY SKILLS & EXPERTISE**

Training Development	Conflict Resolution	Strategic Planning
Leadership	Risk Management	<b>Customer Service</b>
Project Management	Supply Management	Team Building
Program Management	Personnel Development	Critical Thinking

### **EDUCATION**

Master of Business Administration, Syracuse University (projected completion December 2020)

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, Stevens-Henager College (2004)

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Workforce Navigator**

CAMPS (Center for Advanced Manufacturing Puget Sound)

Kent, WA (2019)

- Recruited transitioning military service members and spouses into the manufacturing industry.
- Assisted with planning, giving classroom instruction, writing resumes, and communicating with the candidates regularly to help place them into jobs with CAMPS' member businesses.

## Agent

New York Life

Bellevue, WA (2018)

- Licensed in three states to design and sell life insurance policies to screened and approved clients
- Tracked all sourcing efforts, sales leads, and client communications and sales in the customer relationship management database
- Provided financial assessment and assisted the client in selecting the appropriate insurance products and coverage

# Program Manager (Soldier for Life - Transition Assistance Program)

US Army, 7<sup>th</sup> Infantry Division

Joint Base Lewis-McChord, Tacoma, WA (2017-2018)

- Monitored and analyzed trends for transitioning Soldiers to ensure compliance with federal law
- Developed standard operating procedures for use across the entire organization of over 14,000 people
- Planned and coordinated training for over 35 managers throughout the organization
- Developed relationships and worked with multiple federal agencies, state agencies, and volunteer organizations to build relationships and to foster understanding and cooperation

# Network Operations Officer

US Army, 7<sup>th</sup> Infantry Division

Joint Base Lewis-McChord, Tacoma, WA (2015-2017)

- Planned, developed, published, and assisted in the implementation of all C-Suite operations orders for an organization of over 14,000 people
- Participated in various exercises involving over 3,500 people, representing the department to the organization director
- Planned, developed, published, and assisted in the implementation of annual and quarterly training guidance and leader development programs

# Director

US Army, 35th Signal Brigade, 63d Signal Battalion

Fort Gordon, Augusta, GA (2012 – 2015)

- Director of a 140-member headquarters organization that conducted support to Homeland Defense missions and exercises as the telecommunications provider to a combined organization
- Planned, coordinated, and synchronized multiple significant military training events for the organization in preparation for Homeland Defense operations with an operational budget of approximately \$400,000 per year from long-term planting through completion
- Maintained accountability and readiness of all government resources
- Oversaw the training, readiness, safety, discipline, and morale of 140 Soldiers and their families

## **Network Operations Officer**

US Army, 35th Signal Brigade

Fort Gordon, GA (2012)

- Planned, developed, published, and assisted in the implementation of all C-Suite operations orders for an organization of over 2,600 people
- Participated in various exercises involving over 600 people, representing the department to the organization director
- Planned, developed, published, and assisted in the implementation of annual and quarterly training guidance and leader development programs
- Planned and hosted a unit tour for 11 foreign senior military officers from Africa

# **Deputy Director**

US Army, 11th Signal Brigade

Fort Huachuca, Sierra Vista, AZ (2011)

- Coordinated command and control of four expeditionary signal battalions, providing and protecting expeditionary communications and computer systems and networks for 4-star headquarters with a strength of over 2,600 Soldiers distributed across 3 installations
- Responsible for oversight and management of the brigade staff and the synchronization of personnel, intelligence, maintenance, logistics, and food service needs
- Supervised the brigade's annual budget of over \$14 million

#### Staff Officer

US Army, 11th Signal Brigade, 86th Signal Battalion

Fort Huachuca, Sierra Vista, AZ and Afghanistan (2010 - 2011)

- Established the only stand-alone school in Afghanistan, capable of hosting four separate classes for communications and IT training to US Forces and partner military forces in Afghanistan. Developed classes based on regulatory requirements per military occupational specialty as well as mission requirements
- Integrated Pearson VUE test center into the school for US Forces to take proctored tests which resulted in over 75
   Soldiers receiving industry standard certifications
- Acted as the logistics officer for the first three months of the rotation to Afghanistan
- Tracked equipment from US to Afghanistan with no losses
- Planned and tracked movement of equipment and personnel from hub to outlying sites and back with no losses
- Planned, developed, assessed, and assisted in the implementation of annual and quarterly regulatory training guidance for four departments in an organization of over 1,000 Soldiers and Department of the Army civilians
- Developed and maintained long- and short-range training calendars